<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="C:\RainbowCVS\CVSROOT\Rainbow\rb_documentation\Style\Default.xsl"?>
<dita xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:noNamespaceSchemaLocation="C:\Documents and Settings\Jeremy\Desktop\dita13\dita13\schema\ditabase.xsd">
	<topic id="core-page-en" xml:lang="en">
		<title>The Rainbow 'Page' Class</title>
		<titlealts>
			<navtitle>Page Class</navtitle>
			<searchtitle>Page Class</searchtitle>
		</titlealts>
		<shortdesc>The Rainbow Page Class inherits from System.Web.UI.Page and extends the class to support Rainbow functionality.</shortdesc>
		<prolog>
			<author type="creator">Jeremy Esland</author>
			<critdates>
				<created date="2004-09-11"/>
			</critdates>
			<metadata>
				<audience type="programmer" job="programming" experiencelevel="expert"/>
				<category>Core Classes</category>
				<keywords>
					<keyword>Core</keyword>
					<keyword>Class</keyword>
					<keyword>UI</keyword>
				</keywords>
				<prodinfo>
					<prodname>Rainbow Portal</prodname>
					<vrmlist>
						<vrm modification="1" release="2004-09-11" version="1.0"/>
					</vrmlist>
					<component>/UI/Page.cs</component>
				</prodinfo>
			</metadata>
		</prolog>
		<body>
			<section>
				<title>Purpose</title>
				<p>The Rainbow.UI.Page class inherits from System.UI.Page, extending it's functionality and features. The class is 
				the "pivot point" for Rainbow pages: the code-behind for DesktopDefault.aspx (the main Rainbow page) inherits from 
				Rainbow.UI.Page and is therefore provided with the full range of security, content and other functionality. The "higher 
				level" pages (used for some admin functions, etc.) themselves inherit from Rainbow.UI.Page to add more specific security 
				features. This class is responsible for building the actual HTML output markup outside of the &lt;form&gt;, i.e. the 
				&lt;head&gt; element, including page title, all CSS references, any Javascript blocks or imports, the page meta elements, etc.</p>
			</section>
			<section>
				<title>Features</title>
				<p>On top of the functionality inherited from the System.UI.Page class, the Rainbow.UI.Page class adds the following:</p>
				<ul>
					<li>Standard "in-module" buttons for Update, Delete and Cancel with overridable Click event handlers and role-based authorization. 
					The Add and Delete buttons automatically flush the module content from cache if it is there. The Delete button provides an automatic client-side confirmation dialog to prevent unintended deletions.</li>
					<li>Easy access to appropriate Portal, Tab, Module, Theme and Item properties.</li>
					<li>Properties for the storage and control of:
					<ul>
							<li>Page Title (with localization support)</li>
							<li>standard META elements: keywords, description, encoding</li>
							<li>a site-wide additional META entry which can be overriden per tab from admin settings screens</li>
							<li>a META element collection, enabling module code to add additional META elements to the page output as needed</li>
							<li>a CSS file collection, enabling module code to add additional CSS file references to the page output as needed</li>
							<li>a CSS style collection, enabling module code to add embedded CSS rule-sets to the page output as needed</li>
							<li>a Client Script collection, enabling module code to add Javascript file references to the page output as needed (as distinct from the .NET standard Client Script Block functionality)</li>
							<li>a &lt;body&gt; onload function call collection, enabling module code to add onload script triggers to the page output as needed</li>
							<li>a &lt;body&gt; attributes string, enabling other attributes to be added to the &lt;body&gt; element from Site Settings</li>
							<li>a DOCTYPE string, enabling the page DOCTYPE to be specified from Site Settings</li>
							<li>a standardised Pop-Up helper, enabling easy control of child window launching from module buttons (with full cross-browser support and specific accessibility features)</li>
						</ul>
					</li>
					<li>Helper methods: Is...Registered(...) and Register...(...) for:
					<ul>
							<li>CSS files references</li>
							<li>CSS embedded styles</li>
							<li>Client Scripts</li>
							<li>&lt;body&gt; onload function calls</li>
							<li>Additional META elements</li>
							<li>named pop-up windows</li>
						</ul>
					</li>
					<li>Full support for Rainbow's role-based security.</li>
					<li>An overriden Render method (see details below).</li>
				</ul>
			</section>
			<section>
				<title>The Render method</title>
				<p>Rainbow.UI.Page has an overriden Render method which completely controls the final HTML markup of the page outside of the &lt;form&gt; element itself. Any .aspx page which inherits directly or indirectly from Rainbow.UI.Page is effectively stripped of all content above and below
				the &lt;form&gt; element. This is then replaced with markup built from the various properties stored in the Page class (see above). Thus whatever markup exists outside the &lt;form&gt; element never makes into into the final output page and is there only to support the origination
				and maintenance of that .aspx file by developers. </p>
				<p>The Render method builds the &lt;html&gt;, &lt;head&gt; and &lt;body&gt; elements. It populates the &lt;head&gt; element with &lt;title&gt;, &lt;meta&gt;,&lt;link&gt;, &lt;style&gt; and &lt;script&gt; elements as approriate. It adds any required attributes to the &lt;body&gt; element.</p>
				<note type="attention">Since this new method replaces any &lt;head&gt; element specified in the source .aspx file, it is no longer necessary to use &lt;head id="htmlHead" runat="server"&gt;, which supported the old way of building the &lt;head&gt; element. Nevertheless, it won't do any harm if it is present.</note>
			</section>
		</body>
		<related-links>
			<linklist  scope="peer" format="dita">
				<title>Related Topics</title>
				<link href="/rb_documentation/DesktopDefault.aspx/DesktopDefault.aspx.resx">
					<linktext>DesktopDefault.aspx</linktext>
				</link>
				<link href="/rb_documentation/UI/WebControls/PortalModuleControl.cs/PortalModuleControl.cs.resx">
					<linktext>PortalModuleControl class</linktext>
				</link>
				<link href="/rb_documentation/UI/WebControls/ModuleButton.cs/ModuleButton.cs.resx">
					<linktext>ModuleButton class</linktext>
				</link>
				<link href="/rb_documentation/DesktopModules/SiteSettings/SiteSettings.ascx/SiteSettings.ascx.resx">
					<linktext>Site Settings</linktext>
				</link>
			</linklist>
		</related-links>
	</topic>
</dita>
